[
   {
      "front":"Ego",
      "back":"A child's early experience in coping with external demands leads to the development of ______."
   },
   {
      "front":"May function reasonably well in society.",
      "back":"People with personality disorders..."
   },
   {
      "front":"Obsessions",
      "back":"Persistent repetitive thoughts"
   },
   {
      "front":"Behaviorism",
      "back":"Emphasizes the dominance of heredity over environment."
   },
   {
      "front":"Dissociative Disorder",
      "back":"Multiple personality is a type of..."
   },
   {
      "front":"Myelin Sheath",
      "back":"Increases the velocity of conduction of the action potential along the axon"
   },
   {
      "front":"Accomodation",
      "back":"Modifying schema to account for new info, change in curvature of the lens that enables the eye to focus on objects at various distances"
   },
   {
      "front":"Benjamin Whorf's linguistic relativity hypothesis",
      "back":"Different languages predispose those individuals who speak to them to think about the world in different ways"
   },
   {
      "front":"Blind Spot",
      "back":"The place in the retina where the optic nerve exits to the brain is called the..."
   },
   {
      "front":"metacognition",
      "back":"Thinking about thinking"
   },
   {
      "front":"Law of Effect",
      "back":"Thorndike argued that responses leading to rewards are more likely to be repeated, responses leading to punishments are less likely to be repeated."
   },
   {
      "front":"Causation",
      "back":"Correlation does not equal ____."
   },
   {
      "front":"Clinical Disorders",
      "back":"Axis I"
   },
   {
      "front":"Personality Disorders and Mental Retardation",
      "back":"Axis II"
   },
   {
      "front":"General Medical Condition",
      "back":"Axis III"
   },
   {
      "front":"Psychosocial & Environmental Factors",
      "back":"Axis IV"
   },
   {
      "front":"Global Assessment of Functioning",
      "back":"Axis V"
   },
   {
      "front":"Histronic Personality Disorder",
      "back":"A person acts very dramatic and emotional to get attention"
   },
   {
      "front":"Schizoids",
      "back":"People who are withdrawn and are not bothered by their lack of social relationships. They often have flat or inapproprate emotional responses."
   },
   {
      "front":"General Anxiety Disorder",
      "back":"a recurring state of anxiety, fear, restlessness, and tenseness"
   },
   {
      "front":"Dysthymic Disorder",
      "back":"a mood disorder involving a pattern of comparatively mild depression that lasts for at least two years"
   },
   {
      "front":"Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation",
      "back":"Direct stimulation of the cerebral cortex induced by magnetic fields generated outside the skull"
   },
   {
      "front":"Positive Symptoms",
      "back":"symptoms of schizophrenia involving behavioral excesses, such as hallucinations and delusions."
   },
   {
      "front":"Negative Symptoms",
      "back":"Schizophrenic symptoms that involve behavioral deficits, such as flattened emotions, social withdrawal, apathy, impaired attention, and poverty of speech."
   },
   {
      "front":"Paranoid Schizophrenia",
      "back":"A type of schizophrenia that is dominated by delusions of persecution along with delusions of grandeur."
   },
   {
      "front":"Dissocial Personality Disorder",
      "back":"complete lack of interest in social obligations"
   },
   {
      "front":"Borderline Personality Disorder",
      "back":"A personality disorder characterized by instability of interpersonal relationships, self-image, and emotions, and marked impulsivity"
   },
   {
      "front":"Phallic Stage",
      "back":"children are obssessed with genitals, oedipus/electra complex is formed"
   },
   {
      "front":"endomorph",
      "back":"fat, round, easy going, sociable"
   },
   {
      "front":"ectomorph",
      "back":"Thin, has trouble gaining weight"
   },
   {
      "front":"treatment of schizophrenia",
      "back":"Antipsychotic drugs"
   },
   {
      "front":"Neuroleptics",
      "back":"Antipsychotic drugs (i.e. chlorpromazine, clozapine, thorazine, and haldol)"
   },
   {
      "front":"Dissociative Fugue",
      "back":"disorder in which one travels away from home and is unable to remember details of his past, including often his identity"
   },
   {
      "front":"Biopsychosocial Perspective",
      "back":"assumes that biological, sociocultural, and psychological factors combine and interact to produce psychological disorders"
   },
   {
      "front":"Mood Disorder",
      "back":"a disorder in which a person undergoes changes in mood that seem inappropriate or extreme"
   },
   {
      "front":"Major Depressive Disorder",
      "back":"most common type of depressive disorder, characterized by periods of downcast mood, feelings of worthlessness, and loss of interest in pleasurable activities"
   },
   {
      "front":"Depersonalization",
      "back":"feelings of detachment from one's mental processes or body"
   },
   {
      "front":"Dissociative Identity",
      "back":"a dissociative disorder in which a person appears to have more than one identity, each of which behaves in a different way"
   },
   {
      "front":"Dissociative Amnesia",
      "back":"Dissociative disorder characterized by the sudden and extensive inability to recall important personal information, usually after extreme stress/trauma"
   },
   {
      "front":"Lewin",
      "back":"Father of Social Psychology, Tested 3 styles of teaching a class- authoritative, permissive, and authoritarian. (authoritative was most effective)"
   },
   {
      "front":"Rabin",
      "back":"focused on positive interpretations of stressful situations"
   },
   {
      "front":"Acetylcholine",
      "back":"a neurotransmitter that enables learning and memory and also triggers muscle contraction (not enough = alzheimers)"
   },
   {
      "front":"Dopamine",
      "back":"too much = schizophrenia, too little = Parkinson's disease"
   },
   {
      "front":"GABA",
      "back":"major inhibitory neurotransmitter"
   },
   {
      "front":"Glutamate",
      "back":"A major excitatory neurotransmitter; involved in memory. Too much = migraines"
   },
   {
      "front":"Serotonin",
      "back":"Comes from the sun, makes you happy"
   },
   {
      "front":"Norepinephrine",
      "back":"helps control alertness and arousal, not enough = ADHD"
   },
   {
      "front":"TAT",
      "back":"look at the picture, tell me a story"
   },
   {
      "front":"Rorschach",
      "back":"inkblot test"
   },
   {
      "front":"william james",
      "back":"founder of functionalism; published first psychology textbook"
   },
   {
      "front":"medical model",
      "back":"the concept that diseases have physical causes that can be diagnosed, treated, and, in most cases, cured"
   },
   {
      "front":"MMPI",
      "back":"the most widely researched and clinically used of all personality tests. Originally used to identify emotional disorders, this test is now used for many other screening puposes"
   },
   {
      "front":"person centered therapy",
      "back":"The therapeutic technique based on humanistic theory which is non-directive and empathic."
   },
   {
      "front":"Retina",
      "back":"In vision, transduction occurs within the ____."
   },
   {
      "front":"Lateral Hypothalamus",
      "back":"Stimulated = Hungry, Lesioned/Destroyed = Not Hungry"
   },
   {
      "front":"Ventromedial Hypothalamus",
      "back":"Stimulated = Not Hungry, Lesioned/Destroyed = Hungry"
   },
   {
      "front":"Latent Learning",
      "back":"Learning that occurs but is not apparent until there is an incentive to demonstrate it."
   },
   {
      "front":"Piaget's Stages",
      "back":"sensorimotor stage, preoperational stage, concrete operational stage, formal operations"
   },
   {
      "front":"Morpheme",
      "back":"in language, the smallest unit that carries meaning"
   },
   {
      "front":"Phoneme",
      "back":"in a spoken language, the smallest distinctive sound unit"
   },
   {
      "front":"Syntax",
      "back":"word order"
   },
   {
      "front":"Retinal Disparity",
      "back":"Binocular cue for depth perception"
   },
   {
      "front":"cones",
      "back":"people who are color blind have issues with _____."
   },
   {
      "front":"Gate Control Theory",
      "back":"pain is modulated by a spinal gate that determines whether a pain signal is allowed to go on to the brain"
   },
   {
      "front":"Display Rules",
      "back":"cross-cultural guidelines for how and when to express emotions"
   },
   {
      "front":"Diathesis-Stress Approach",
      "back":"Disorders are a result of predisposed, biological factors triggered by the environment"
   },
   {
      "front":"Preoperational",
      "back":"Children cease to exhibit egocentricism during the ______ Stage."
   },
   {
      "front":"Schacter-Singer Theory of Emotion",
      "back":"Cognitive labels in response to physiological excitation"
   },
   {
      "front":"James-Lange Theory of Emotion",
      "back":"I'm crying, so I must be sad."
   },
   {
      "front":"Canon-Bard Theory of Emotion",
      "back":"We feel emotions, then act upon them."
   },
   {
      "front":"Stage 1 Sleep",
      "back":"Between asleep & awake, only a few minutes, theta waves"
   },
   {
      "front":"Stage 2 Sleep",
      "back":"Sleep spindles, 20 min."
   },
   {
      "front":"Stage 3 Sleep",
      "back":"Transitional stage between light and deep sleep"
   },
   {
      "front":"Stage 4 Sleep",
      "back":"Deep sleep, slow delta waves, bedwetting & sleepwalking"
   },
   {
      "front":"REM Sleep",
      "back":"Vivid dreaming, increased brain activity, limited muscle activity"
   },
   {
      "front":"Psychopaths",
      "back":"Personality disorder, lack empathy"
   },
   {
      "front":"Organic Mental Disorders",
      "back":"Result from a developmental abnormality in the brain, can be temporary or permanent"
   },
   {
      "front":"ablation",
      "back":"removal or destruction of brain tissue in a surgical procedure"
   },
   {
      "front":"acquisition",
      "back":"a process in classical conditioning by which the association of a neutral stimulus with a natural stimulus is first established"
   },
   {
      "front":"operant conditioning",
      "back":"a type of conditioning in which behavior is strengthened if followed by a reinforcer or diminished if followed by a punisher."
   }
]